<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My Recursive Time</title>
    <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My Recursive Time</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 10: Presentation day</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/10/</guid>
      <description>Today I signed up to give the target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo; vulnerability talk. It was at 1745, so I had plenty of time to focus on other stuff. I started vbvy building the RAM chips for the Nand2Tetris class, and then decided to further advance on the ReactJS book. I programmed at least until 1720 and then went out to socialize before the talk. The ReactJS book is becoming the sort of book where you actually think there have to be other ways of doing this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 9: Managing FOMO (Fear of missing out)</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/9/</guid>
      <description>Today I started by watching the Algorithms class for week 2. I was so hooked on React (and coding mostly) that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t to keen on watching it. I was wrong, the class is enticing and teaches complex concepts in a really great way. After that I was able to understand the afternoon algo&amp;rsquo;s meeting on rendering fractals with the CPU or the GPU asypthotic complexity. I have set myself a goal of spending 1 hour at these meetings so I don&amp;rsquo;t get distracted from nadn2tetris and the ReactJS book, this time I&amp;rsquo;m going to finish it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 8: Here comes React!</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/8/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I played Overwatch until 1 am, I will blame Renato, everything it&amp;rsquo;s always his fault. I thought this woudl not be a productive day, but I have to say, Esen is right when he says he codes better when he is a little bit tired, this way the brain focuses only at the task at hand and doesn&amp;rsquo;t wander around so much. I arrived and met James, toyed a bit with my phishing site and couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a single famous site that hadn&amp;rsquo;t prevented the attack yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 7: Holiday</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/7/</guid>
      <description>Today was Martir Luther King Jr, so it was a national holiday. Still, many of us came to RC to keep going. I decided to walk here for the first time, it&amp;rsquo;s only around 10km away, and this really helped understand what was going on above ground.
I met with roberto, and after shwing to him the referrer vulnerability project, I decided to polish and finish it. It is now online on mi site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6: Phishing</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/6/</guid>
      <description>So, today was sunday, but we could still come to RC, it&amp;rsquo;s open 24x7! I decided I wanted to try to implement a website idea I had a while ago while documenting on the referrer browser functionality. The referrer functionality allows a website that was opened with a target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo; attribute, to take control of the original website location context, so it could change the previous website while you are not looking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5: Algorithms</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/5/</guid>
      <description>Today I arrived and met Alessandro, he is from the mini batch, so this is his last day. From him I learned about some amazing initiatives being developed like TablaViva. He is working in creating a reactive environment that will react to defined facts. I find itr fascinating because I think this could really end up being a great tool to teach kids about logic and how computers work. Initiatives like Cubetto are nice, but their goal is to be used inside of your house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4: Game night</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 18:07:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/4/</guid>
      <description>Today I forgot my laptop and realized only too late, so by the time I got back to RC with it, it was already 1230. I started by finishing the Chips excercises. I thought the 16 bit ones were going to be more challenging, but they were just what they are meant to be, 16 bit chips (duh), so here is a 16 bit implementation of the AND chip</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3: A different mindset</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 18:07:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/3/</guid>
      <description>So, today I arrived at RC at 820, I was surprised to be the first, so I poured myself some coffee and started working on the HDL Chip Design excercises. I had to go back to the NAND descripcion videos and pick up some pen and paper to actually understand how electronic circuits work. After some pen and paper hacking I manage to compose the basic circuits, then, reviewing implementations, and reviewing the book again, I end up with valid Mux and Demux chips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2: Nand2Tetris</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 18:07:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/2/</guid>
      <description>Today I started with Nand2Tetris, it is this amazing course from the Hebrew University of Jerusalem where they teach you from scratch how to buld an actual computer. We begin by learning how to build basic logical gates or computer chips with a Hardware Design Language, and from there, you begin your travel to higher and higher abstractions. The actual path is:
 Boolean Logic Boolean Arithmetic Sequential Logic Machine Language Computer Architecture Assembler Virtual Machine: Stack Arithmetic Virtual Machine: Program Control High Level Language Compiler: Syntax Analysis Compiler: Code Generation Operating System Postscript  So basically you begin building basic CPU chips using only NAND gates and end up with a fully fledged computer capable of runing not only the OS that you built, but also any software you right and compile for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1: Arrival</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 13:59:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/1/</guid>
      <description>I almost arrive late (or don&amp;rsquo;t arrive at all) to my first day. My flight from panama got turned around because of an accident due to bad weather at JFk airport. Luckyly in the end we embarqued in a charter direct to NYC.
As I was knackered by the 2 day trip and had barely slept, I&amp;rsquo;ll just bulletpoint what I remember:
 RC tour, didin&amp;rsquo;t really hear what Nick was saying, will figure it out on the way Another peruvian in the same batch!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>