<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Recursive Time</title>
    <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Recursive Time</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 09:56:01 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.ondoheer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>And I thought I was done...</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/docker-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/docker-2/</guid>
      <description>So, I fixed the CORS issue, and as I suspected, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a CORS issue per se. It was really frustrating, because it meant there was something I wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting right. Laurent came to help me (again) and we could not finish tackling the problem because I had a patient call. It was kind of frustrating, I wanted to move on and keep on learning new stuff! Oh, and my Skype account got Hacked as I was having my session!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parcel testing, is it a good idea?</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/parcel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/parcel/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday James and I decided to test parcel as React/Redux project bundler. At first it seemed magical, we just removed Webpack and everything just worked, we could even import the root scss file directly into our index.html and it would take care of everything. So much magic came at a cost we are still assesing though.
 If you import an empty scss file, it breaks If you import the same file (js or scss/css) from your html and your main .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker...Docker...Docker</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/docker/</guid>
      <description>Last week I decided to finally tackle Docker. As always, I set myself the goal to be done with it at most by friday night. I maged to, on friday at 11pm at my house, but it was hard as hell.
I have a bit of DevOps experience, I mostly know how to configure linux servers by hand, and have used tools such as Pythons Fabric library, I have even played or worked on allready built Docker projects, but I felt I needed to understand it more, and see how to deploy more complex projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devops and Debugging</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/devops-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/devops-debugging/</guid>
      <description>Today is thursday and I feel I have spend the whole week just debugging stuff. The nice part, is everything works now, and I felt no rush to be done quick because I had to go to work at my practice or the client&amp;rsquo;s budget had alreasdy run out and we were losing money. This was really good. It made me value what having time to really get to understand a problem does for the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack the Deep</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/hack-the-deep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/hack-the-deep/</guid>
      <description>DISCLAIMER: it seems the website theme doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize the images direction and just shows them all in landscape, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll fix this
From february 9 to 11 I joined some recursers at the Hack the Deep Hackaton. It was amazing.
Different to other Hackatons, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t an open project one. The American Museum of Natural History had worked with some of their scientists to come up with challenges they needed technical skills to solve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wait what?? where did it go?</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/february/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/february/</guid>
      <description>So, Here it goes again. First I stopped publishing, then I took my whole server down. The story has many parts, but the importante parts:
 I finished the Go backend and decided not to use it. Go is amazing, but if I am not going to be using it regularly, it makes no sense to mantain an app in a language I will abrely use. I rebuild it all from scratch using Flask Then I decided to build the frontend in ReactJS, and it was great (more coming soon) I took part the Hack The Deep AMNH hackaton and we won!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 18: Golang, Algos and I need to sleep!</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/18/</guid>
      <description>I stayed up late reading all about Golang frameworks, their patterns, how they recommend to work, and what it’s good for. Most people didin’t recommend it for fast changing projects, and it’s strength is on concurrency, so for small MPV’s it makes no sense. Still I feel it’s really opening my mind to diferent programming paradigms, so I’ll finish building the small redo of my expense tracker app with go and react.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 17: Redux, check? Golang otw</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/17/</guid>
      <description>Today I finished refactoring my DiceRoller app to Redux. It worked! James helped me grasp the subtleties ob how I should dispatch the events, and the pattern is actually exciting! I still need a lot more practice, I’m thinking about creating a PWA for the cthulu RPG based on karels design.
I started learning Golang today by following their tutorial on webservers. I managed to create a simple webapp and failed when I tried to create composable templates, but I’m sure I’ll have it figured out by tomorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 16: Stay at home React Developer</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/16/</guid>
      <description>I stayed at home to wait for the Fedex delivery, and now it says it might come at any time from 12-20… I’ll try to make the best out of this day. I finished my basic version of the Dice Roller App, and now I will go through the Redux tutorials to see if I can refactor my code to use it.
By the end of the day I had to things clear: 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 15: Writting Assembly, Blood Batteries, Google Glass</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/15/</guid>
      <description>I arrived really early to make the most out of the day. I started by watching week 3 of the Algo’s course, and then spend the morning doing the nand2tetris assembly psets. It was fun, I coundl’t handle working as an assembly coder, but doing it just for fun was amazing. It reminded me of the logic problems, which seemed more like a puzzle than homework.
Ann brought her old Google Glass set today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 12-13: React take 2</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/12-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/12-13/</guid>
      <description>On saturday I decided to stay home until I had fully understood Redux and the flux pattern. I did the online course by the Redux creator, where he tought how to build Redux from scratch and use it. It was enlighting, but when I tried to apply it to my kanban project, I realized I really had no real hands experience with React and I was skipping steps. So I rewinded and started React on Treehouse for I knew they would have nice basic projects to complete.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 14: So this is how hardware instructions work!</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/14/</guid>
      <description>I started by finishing the React Router tutorial, and then forced myself to stop coding (really hard) to watch the next week of nand2tetris. It stared by explaining the hack programming language and it&amp;rsquo;s interface. It was interesting, it is simmilar to what I had seen of Assembly language, but the really cool part came when I started learning about how writting pixels to a screen works. First, it is so basic anyone can figure it out, but once you start seeing how it goes into the CPU architecture and how it starts loading the instructions per clock cycle, I realized what is it that is happening when a program that consumes a lot of memory (ussually bugged) freezes the PC screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 11: NLP &amp; Drinks</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/11/</guid>
      <description>Today I spent most of the day practicing with React. The book had become a little outdated and was starting to work on Animations. I called James to talk about it, and see if it was a good use of my time to actually do it like that. He did not only say it was rubish, but also gave me an amazing 2h talk on React, funtional principles and components composition for stateless systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 10: Presentation day</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/10/</guid>
      <description>Today I signed up to give the target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo; vulnerability talk. It was at 1745, so I had plenty of time to focus on other stuff. I started vbvy building the RAM chips for the Nand2Tetris class, and then decided to further advance on the ReactJS book. I programmed at least until 1720 and then went out to socialize before the talk. The ReactJS book is becoming the sort of book where you actually think there have to be other ways of doing this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 9: Managing FOMO (Fear of missing out)</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/9/</guid>
      <description>Today I started by watching the Algorithms class for week 2. I was so hooked on React (and coding mostly) that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t to keen on watching it. I was wrong, the class is enticing and teaches complex concepts in a really great way. After that I was able to understand the afternoon algo&amp;rsquo;s meeting on rendering fractals with the CPU or the GPU asypthotic complexity. I have set myself a goal of spending 1 hour at these meetings so I don&amp;rsquo;t get distracted from nadn2tetris and the ReactJS book, this time I&amp;rsquo;m going to finish it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 8: Here comes React!</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/8/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I played Overwatch until 1 am, I will blame Renato, everything it&amp;rsquo;s always his fault. I thought this woudl not be a productive day, but I have to say, Esen is right when he says he codes better when he is a little bit tired, this way the brain focuses only at the task at hand and doesn&amp;rsquo;t wander around so much. I arrived and met James, toyed a bit with my phishing site and couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a single famous site that hadn&amp;rsquo;t prevented the attack yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 7: Holiday</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/7/</guid>
      <description>Today was Martir Luther King Jr, so it was a national holiday. Still, many of us came to RC to keep going. I decided to walk here for the first time, it&amp;rsquo;s only around 10km away, and this really helped understand what was going on above ground.
I met with roberto, and after shwing to him the referrer vulnerability project, I decided to polish and finish it. It is now online on mi site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 6: Phishing</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/6/</guid>
      <description>So, today was sunday, but we could still come to RC, it&amp;rsquo;s open 24x7! I decided I wanted to try to implement a website idea I had a while ago while documenting on the referrer browser functionality. The referrer functionality allows a website that was opened with a target=&amp;rdquo;_blank&amp;rdquo; attribute, to take control of the original website location context, so it could change the previous website while you are not looking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 5: Algorithms</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 09:56:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/5/</guid>
      <description>Today I arrived and met Alessandro, he is from the mini batch, so this is his last day. From him I learned about some amazing initiatives being developed like TablaViva. He is working in creating a reactive environment that will react to defined facts. I find itr fascinating because I think this could really end up being a great tool to teach kids about logic and how computers work. Initiatives like Cubetto are nice, but their goal is to be used inside of your house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 4: Game night</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 18:07:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/4/</guid>
      <description>Today I forgot my laptop and realized only too late, so by the time I got back to RC with it, it was already 1230. I started by finishing the Chips excercises. I thought the 16 bit ones were going to be more challenging, but they were just what they are meant to be, 16 bit chips (duh), so here is a 16 bit implementation of the AND chip</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3: A different mindset</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 18:07:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/3/</guid>
      <description>So, today I arrived at RC at 820, I was surprised to be the first, so I poured myself some coffee and started working on the HDL Chip Design excercises. I had to go back to the NAND descripcion videos and pick up some pen and paper to actually understand how electronic circuits work. After some pen and paper hacking I manage to compose the basic circuits, then, reviewing implementations, and reviewing the book again, I end up with valid Mux and Demux chips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2: Nand2Tetris</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 18:07:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/2/</guid>
      <description>Today I started with Nand2Tetris, it is this amazing course from the Hebrew University of Jerusalem where they teach you from scratch how to buld an actual computer. We begin by learning how to build basic logical gates or computer chips with a Hardware Design Language, and from there, you begin your travel to higher and higher abstractions. The actual path is:
 Boolean Logic Boolean Arithmetic Sequential Logic Machine Language Computer Architecture Assembler Virtual Machine: Stack Arithmetic Virtual Machine: Program Control High Level Language Compiler: Syntax Analysis Compiler: Code Generation Operating System Postscript  So basically you begin building basic CPU chips using only NAND gates and end up with a fully fledged computer capable of runing not only the OS that you built, but also any software you right and compile for it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1: Arrival</title>
      <link>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 13:59:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.ondoheer.com/posts/1/</guid>
      <description>I almost arrive late (or don&amp;rsquo;t arrive at all) to my first day. My flight from panama got turned around because of an accident due to bad weather at JFk airport. Luckyly in the end we embarqued in a charter direct to NYC.
As I was knackered by the 2 day trip and had barely slept, I&amp;rsquo;ll just bulletpoint what I remember:
 RC tour, didin&amp;rsquo;t really hear what Nick was saying, will figure it out on the way Another peruvian in the same batch!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>